An epic adventure and passionate romance unfold against the
panorama of a frontier wilderness ravaged by war.
The Last of the Mohicans is a action, history,
romance film directed by Michael Mann.
In war-torn colonial America, in the midst of a bloody battle between British, the French and Native American allies,
the aristocratic daughter of a British Colonel and her party are captured by a group of Huron warriors.
Fortunately, a group of three Mohican trappers comes to their rescue.
Hawkeye, played by Daniel Day-Lewis.
Cora, played by Madeleine Stowe.
Alice, played by Jodhi May.
Chingachgook, played by Russell Means.
Magua, played by Wes Studi.
Uncas, played by Eric Schweig.
The Last of the Mohicans is a 1992 American epic historical drama war film co-produced and directed by Michael Mann, who co-wrote the
screenplay with Christopher Crowe, based on the 1826 novel of the same name by James Fenimore Cooper and its 1936 film adaptation.
The film is set in 1757 during the French and Indian War.
It stars Daniel Day-Lewis, Madeleine Stowe, and Jodhi May in the leading roles, and features Russell
Means, Wes Studi, Eric Schweig, Steven Waddington, Maurice Roëves, and Patrice Chéreau.
The film was released in the United States on September 25, 1992.
It received generally positive reviews from
critics and was a commercial success.
It won the Academy Award for Best Sound, the only Academy
Award won by a film directed by Mann to date.
It was also nominated for seven BAFTA Awards, including Best Actor in a Leading Role
for Day-Lewis, and won Best Cinematography and Best Make-up Artist.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, love triangle,
native american, revenge, interracial relationship.
The tone is emotional.